Nikhil Kumar Dasari

Python Full Stack Web Developer

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am highly motivated and passionate professional working as a Python Full Stack Web developer over 2.5+ years of industrial experience in Designing, Development and Maintenance based on Django framework. Professional web applications development experience using Django, Python and inclusive of experience in UI.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Python Full Stack Web Developer Syllogic IT Solutions Pvt. LTD, Hyderabad, India

February 2019 - Present

I played a significant role as a full stack developer in the development of an ecommerce website for the client. Later performed the role of a back-end developer in a project implementation team.

- Application Development using Django Framework
- Also involve in the application development using Python, HTML5, CSS and JavaScript
- Developed views and templates with Python and Django's view controller and template language to create user friendly website interface
- Used GIT version control system and Python tools for Visual Studio Code IDE
- Change requests and bug-fixes
- Optimizations and customizations according to the need of different implementation layer
- Documentation

Assistant System Engineer Syllogic IT Solutions Pvt. LTD, Hyderabad, India

April 2018 - February 2019

I went through a training program of 2 months in Python. And after training, I was assigned with the team responsible for the development of a Django based web application.

- Assisted development team by performing initial level of debugging
- Worked on some modules as a backed developer
- Project also used other technologies like JavaScript, bootstrap for the front-end HTML layout
- Gained a prerequisite knowledge of functioning of a web application, practical MVT concepts

EDUCATION

Kakinada Institute of Engineering & Technology, Korangi — B.Tech

September 2013 - July 2017

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering.

CONTACT DETAILS

(+91 9110564309

nikhildasari95@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Python
- Django Framework
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Jinja2
- SQLite
- MySQL

TOOLS

- VS Code
- GIT

SOCIAL

- LinkedIn
 <u>/in/nikhilkumardasari</u>
- Github <u>@NikhilKumarDasari</u>
- Website
 @nikhilkumardasari.io

LANGUAGES

- Telugu
- English

INTERESTS

- Watching Movies
- Reading
- Cooking